scoopon.com.au 2018-10-03

# Privacy Policy | Scoopon

## 1\. Privacy Statement

1.1 Scoopon and each of its Related Bodies Corporate (also referred to as “We” in this Privacy Policy) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal information. Our privacy policy outlines our approach to privacy and how we collect, use and protect your personal information. It also sets out your rights in relation to accessing the personal information we collect and hold about you. We are bound by the Australian Privacy Principles (or APP's) in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth).

This Privacy Policy has been drafted having regard to our obligations under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), the Privacy Amendment (Enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012 which includes the Australian Privacy Principles (collectively, the Privacy Act) and the Spam Act 2003 Cth (Spam Act). This Privacy Policy is a public document and has been prepared in light of Australian Privacy Principle 1 - Open and Transparent Management of Personal Information.

Please take a few minutes to review this Privacy Policy. By using the Scoopon Website, you are consenting to the Collection, Use and Disclosure of your Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

1.2 Personal information is defined in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and means information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable.

1.3 Our Website may contain links to third party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of any third party websites. We recommend that you review the privacy policy of each website you visit.

## 2\. Collection of Personal Information

2.1 Scoopon only collects personal information for the purposes of conducting our business as an online retailer and trader. The personal information we collect from you will include information you give us when you:

2.1.1 register or subscribe to our Website;

2.1.2 complete a transaction with us; and

2.1.3 contact us.

2.2 The personal information that we collect on individuals may include, but is not limited to:

2.2.1 your name;

2.2.2 your contact details including your email, home address and billing address;

2.2.3 your payment details; and

2.4 At or before the time, or, if that is not practicable, as soon as practicable after, we Collect your Personal Information, we will notify you of the matters required pursuant to Australian Privacy Principal 5 – Notification of the Collection of Personal Information, by providing you with this Privacy Policy, or by notifying you of how you may access this Privacy Policy.

2.5 Scoopon will not Collect Personal Information secretly or in an underhanded way and will not sell your Personal Information to any third party.

2.6 We may collect personal information from individuals who are not customers of our business but whose personal information is given to us by those individuals via our Website or in the course of a transaction.

2.7 Where reasonably practicable, we attempt to collect information directly from individuals. When we collect information, we will generally explain to the individual why we are collecting it, who we give it to and how we will use or disclose it or, alternatively, those matters will be obvious from the circumstances.

2.8 We will collect personal information from you by lawful and fair means and not in an unreasonably intrusive way.

2.9 When you visit our Website and/or download our app, third parties, may place cookies on your browser to enhance and manage our website and improve our business and the services we provide to you. We and/or Google may use this information to optimise and place advertisements, including advertisements of third party vendors, on our own and third party websites. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and Privacy Policy. By using the website and agreeing to this policy, you grant us permission to place and store cookies on your browser. Cookies may be used by us to collect the following information:

2.9.1 your computer's operating system;

2.9.2 your computer's browser type and capabilities;

2.9.3 your computer's Internet Protocol (IP) address and geolocation;

2.9.4 web pages visited, including how you were referred to each web page; and

2.9.5 web page usage statistics, including the time spent on each web page.

2.10 Cookies can be managed by accessing the individual settings in your browser.

2.11 We will not identify users or their browsing activities, except where required by law or in accordance with our Terms and Conditions of Use and Sale.

2.12 When downloading our app, you will get a window message that tells you what content on your smartphone the app will need access to maps, location and calendar. You can pick and choose which content a particular app can have access to under Settings / Apps / App Permission.

## 3\. Using and Disclosing Your Personal Information

3.1 We will generally use or disclose your personal information only for the primary purpose for which it was collected; or for a related secondary purpose where you would reasonably expect us to use or disclose the personal information for that secondary purpose. We may otherwise use and disclose your personal information if you have given us consent for the use or disclosure or it is required or authorised by law.

3.2 Generally, we use and disclose your personal information for the purpose of providing you with the goods or services that you have requested, or otherwise to enable us to carry out our business as an online retailer of goods and services.

3.3 If those purposes for which we have collected the information involve providing personal information about an individual to any third party, we will take appropriate and reasonable steps to ensure any personal information is protected.

3.4 We will generally only use personal information for marketing if you have given express or implied consent or it is impracticable to seek consent before this use.

3.5 When registering with Scoopon, you consent to Scoopon using your personal information, such as your email address, for direct marketing purposes. This includes sending you deal emails. You may opt out of receiving these direct marketing communications at any time. Our electronic marketing activities will comply with the requirements of the Spam Act 2003 (Cth).

3.6 We may share your information with other members of the Catch Group Pty Ltd, including members that are located outside of Australia. Our Group is comprised of CatchOfTheDay.com.au Pty Ltd, Scoopon Pty Ltd, Mumgo Pty Ltd and their Related Bodies Corporate, as defined in the Corporations Act 2001 (Cth).

3.7 We may also provide your information to third parties that provide services to us, including third parties that provide our payment gateway, marketing, logistics and technology support services. This may include providing your information to third parties that are located outside of Australia. Where your personal information is transferred outside Australia (including the USA, UK, Hong Kong, the Philippines and the EU), we will do so in accordance with APP 8.  
In addition, we may also disclose your information to third parties in order for them to provide services to you, in accordance with our Terms and Conditions of Use and Sale and this Privacy Policy.

## 4\. Security of Your Personal Information

4.1 We take steps to protect the personal information we hold against loss, unauthorised access, use, modification or disclosure and against other misuse. When no longer required, personal information is destroyed in a secure manner or deleted.

## 5\. Access to Your Personal Information and Complaints Procedure

5.1 Under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), you have certain rights to access the personal information we collect and hold about you.

5.2 Generally, we will allow an individual access to the personal information we hold about them within a reasonable time after it is requested. When requesting such access please identify the precise type/s of information requested. You may make a request by contacting our Privacy Officer by way of email to support@scoopon.com.au

5.2 We take those steps reasonable in the circumstances to ensure that the personal information that we collect, use and disclose is accurate, up to date and complete. Where an individual requests to correct information, we will take reasonable steps to correct the information, having regard to the purpose for which it is held. You may lodge a request to correct personal information in the manner outlined in clause 5.2 above.

5.3 To make a complaint about a breach of the Australian Privacy Principles, which includes how we handle your personal information, you may contact our Help Centre or write to us at the address provided below. We will endeavour to respond to your complaint within a reasonable time after it is received. If you are not satisfied by our response, you may acquire further information regarding privacy from the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.

## 6\. Lux Vendor App

6.1 By downloading the Lux Vendor App, this will enable the camera feature of your smartphone to act as a scanner. By having this feature, it will allow a swift redemption to all vouchers that you service.

The Lux Vendor app will also store your login credentials for quick and easy access.

The Lux Vendor app will not have access to any further information stored on your phone including your contacts, photographs and calendar.

Privacy Collection Statement

The personal information that we collect from you will include information you provide us when you

  * register or subscribe to our Website;

  * complete a transaction with us; and

  * contact us.

We may further collect personal information from individuals who are not customers of our business but whose personal information is given to us by those individuals via our website, including our Help Centre, or in the course of a transaction.

All personal information will be collected by lawful means and not in an unreasonably intrusive way.

We will use your personal information for the purpose of providing our services to you. We generally share your information with third parties, so that they may also provide services to you pursuant to transactions you make on our website.

We also generally share your personal information

  * with our sister sites,

  * as required or authorised by law,

  * in accordance with our Terms and Conditions of Use and Sale and our Privacy Policy, with third parties that provide services to us, including third parties that provide our payment gateway, marketing, logistics and technology support services.

This may include providing your information to third parties that are located outside of Australia, including the USA, UK, Hong Kong, the Philippines and the EU.

In cases where personal information has been disclosed to any third party, we will take appropriate steps to ensure your personal information is protected.

Scoopon Privacy Policy provides you with information about how you may:

  * access your personal information held by Scoopon and change that information, and

  * complain about a breach of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and how Scoopon will deal with such a complaint.

Scoopon’s Privacy Collection Statement and Privacy Policy may change from time to time. The latest versions will be available online at <https://scoopon.com.au/privacy-policy>

Privacy Officer  
Scoopon Pty Ltd  
Level 1, 50-56 York St  
South Melbourne, VIC 3205  
Email: support@scoopon.com.au
